Some quick reaction the Saints selected
Jordan Tyson in the draft not a total
surprise kind of seen this one coming
down the pipe a little bit. Meets with
that axis of need.
Probably meets at the axis of value the
major axis here that we can't quite
measure is risk. Um, we know there's
some here it's inherent to it. It's
baked in the injury stuff is all very
real.
But the talent is also extremely real
too. What's your what's your instant
reaction to this selection? Well, I want
to thank you for putting this on my
radar the last 10 to 14 days I would say
through your reporting because if this
had been a bombshell it would have taken
me a little a little while to
to come to terms with it. I mean up
until 10 days ago we were talking about
Tyson as as an injury question mark and
there was some reporting a couple weeks
ago that he might really fall. He wasn't
in a lot of top 10s.
But once you start thinking, okay, this
might be the guy they love and you watch
the tape and and your great article that
you did on neworleans.football with the
routes they ran in college and how they
match the routes that Tyler Shuck throws
to. I mean
if you can just get past it's a big get
past but if you can get past the injury
this would have been a no-brainer. This
would have been a should they trade up
into the top five to get this guy. He
fits exactly what this team needs. I've
been saying I think receiver is number
one. It's a close race with edge rusher
or defensive line
pass rush in general.
And the other guys you can talk
yourselves into Carnell Tate, you can
talk yourself into Kyren Lacy, you know,
some of the guys going later in the
first round are going to have good
careers. This guy is the special one in
this class. He's the special one in this
class. If he's on the field he's the
special one.
And that's very exciting for this team
that is building around Tyler Shuck. It
helps Chris Olave. He doesn't have to do
it all by himself. He doesn't have to
see all the coverage. I would have no
qualms if it weren't for the injury. And
I said this the other night when we were
out at Loft 18.
And it's controversial. I'm not trusting
the Saints medical experts. They've
screwed up a bunch of times before.
Obviously we know that. They've been
burned a bunch of times before. They've
been burned in the first round of the
draft before.
Yeah. So Mickey Loomis even said the
other day, hey when you're picking eight
you want to remove as many questions as
you can. You're not taking risks at and
we're more risk averse at eight. I at
least feel confident when they make this
move that they got good intel that that
made them feel comfortable that they're
they don't think they're taking a risk.
Maybe they are, but they don't think
they're taking a risk. They wouldn't
have done this if they think he's a
50/50 proposition. The fact that they
took him makes me feel a little better
about him weirdly enough.
It's not like whatever they do is fine
by me, but um I don't think if he had
scary medicals and they didn't think
this was overcomeable stuff that they
would have done this this high in the
draft.
It's interesting because
what Mickey said about erasing the um
the question mark and the variables and
all that stuff.
It's interesting because I do think that
they didn't erase everything here
obviously. I mean there's obviously
there's really no way to predict the
hamstring if it's ever going to happen
again or not.
They got it right with Marshaun. They
might not get it right here. They might
get it right here.
The thing that I think is interesting
about that though is
I think with the other options
especially at wide receiver there were
probably question marks on talent. And
there aren't question marks on talent
here. Like you aren't erasing I think
you had had to get there on some other
guys where you were making decisions on
the other factors where this one you're
allowing
talent to be the thing that drives it.
If it works I mean it's a gamble that
that you can see how it absolutely hits.
If you pick you know, you feel like
Carnell Tate isn't at the same level and
you select him
it might not work out the same exact way
which I find that to be kind of
fascinating in a sense. Like there is a
gambling aspect here.
But he is one of those guys one of the
few guys I think in this class that
actually has
franchise altering talent. And that's
what you want in the top 10. When you're
picking in the top 10 what was Sheldon
Rankins at year 12? Like that's close
enough there too. I don't know that you
got the franchise changing talent. I
don't know that you got it with Andrus
Peat. I don't know that I want to see
the team take a safe pick. Obviously I
don't want to see them take a risk
either. I'd rather they pick a guy that
that is all the talent no risk. But I
think if Jordan Tyson's that
being one of the few guys at a position
of premium value in the NFL if there
were no question marks he's probably
pick three pick four not pick you know,
where the Saints got him. So that's
that's a very interesting variable here
for the team.
Overall
let's kind of go through the upsides and
downsides here. I think the upsides are
quite obvious. Let me start with one. I
mean we're seeing
you know, the fan reaction is going to
be
mixed I think right now in the moment.
Um
I wanted someone else. What are they
doing? But I think starting in about 12
hours certainly in about 12 days this
the excitement level is going to be
higher I mean higher than Calvin Banks,
higher than Tally Fuaga, higher than
Sheldon Rankins, higher than Malcolm
Jenkins. Like I'm trying to think of
other guys higher than Andrus Peat.
When's the last time they drafted a guy
that you were just going to be like you
know, get your popcorn out, get in your
seats, you know, whether that's a game,
whether that's practice.
If he's healthy this is going to be the
most exciting new addition I don't want
to say since Reggie Bush, but I mean
like this is a you want to watch this
guy. And this is not driving the Saints
decision making. They're not trying to
sell season tickets or whatever. But we
we we've watched this team draft a lot
of big offensive lineman and big
defensive lineman that don't
automatically move the needle even if
they're smart football choices. This is
a generate excitement pick.
Just keep him on the field and you're
going to want to watch him play.
Yeah, I think he's a really great
player. Watching him play is it's it's
it's a treat. Like I'm going to enjoy
breaking it down even further. I've been
watching him for a while now.
>> [clears throat]
>> Probably not the after catch guy that I
would really have liked them to get. I
mean that's probably something that's
missing a little bit. But he's a go up
and get it guy. Makes acrobatic catches.
Flies in the air. Floats in the air
rather.
Incredible athlete. Probably about 4-5
speed. Like I think he gives them
everything man. He He gives you
not quite the opposite of Olave, but I
think he's opposite where it matters and
and it gives you a little bit of both
things and then you sprinkle in Valey on
top of that. A chance to have a really
really incredibly explosive offense. Um
You know, the fan reaction whatever it
is it is. Like it doesn't ultimately
like
My guys Bun and Marlowe were doing a
space last year and they're on there
screaming and incredibly upset about the
Tyler Shuck pick and then they're making
songs about Tyler Shuck. Like so it can
you can go from screaming screaming to
to singing pretty quick if things work
out the right way. And I think Jordan
Tyson has a chance to be
if the injuries aren't an issue he has a
chance to be a face of the franchise.
Like I think he has that type of talent
and obviously I think that's the thing
that can help elevate Tyler Shuck to new
levels and let them go places they
haven't been yet. They need TD getters.
It can't just be Chris Olave and you
hope for the best with Valey's health.
Which I think brings us to the big
downside though and it isn't just
Tyson's health. I think you now have
three guys that have varying degrees of
question marks on their on their health
status. You got three of them. You got
to go through three layers to get to the
bottom. I guess that's a good thing.
Injuries can happen to anyone. Previous
stuff doesn't always predict future
stuff. Healthy guys can become injured.
All that stuff is is very true, but you
do enter this with a degree of risk on
all three guys which I think preferably
obviously you'd rather not have it be
that way. No, obviously not. But like
you said that's that's part of the
reason why this position was such a big
need. Like
you were so screwed if Chris Olave
wasn't on the field or or even if Deonte
Valey wasn't on the field. You're not
screwed if any one of the three is off
the field right now. Like you just they
can't all get hurt at the same time. And
obviously that could happen when when
you're taking risks at this position.
But now you you've you've got back up.
You've got back up.
And and you know, I could go into a game
without any one of those three guys and
feel like we can make do cuz as we've
said we like the depth on this team.
They just weren't top heavy enough at
that position.
Yeah, I totally agree with that too.
Yeah. Tell me more about this Olave
usage though. I mean Jordan Tyson isn't
Mike Michael Thomas, but is he it's
third and seven? It's it's first and
goal from the eight?
>> Yeah. Is he your guy?
He's absolutely that guy. That's why you
got him. He's going to go up and he's
going to out leap people and his hands
got better last year. Year before that
there were a lot more drops and stuff
last year. There weren't a bunch of
drops. Like he's really good at going up
and getting the ball contested catches.
I think the quality of target will help
him even more on contested catches.
There's a lot of stuff. Um
Sam love it. Like LSU fans are going to
see it. Like there's a lot of crazy
stuff that happens that you know, I
think going up and getting it sometimes
like some of those contested catches
didn't convert because the throw was
just kind of like oh my god. But he gave
himself a chance. But I think more
calm down on schedule type of offense. I
think there's even more to give there.
But it's it's Deonte Valey style of
player in those situations.
But with a supreme athlete. You know, so
I just think there's another level to to
that whole thing. Yeah, he's your goal
line guy. He's your third and seven guy.
He's your hard down guy.
And he's he's going to draw attention
too. And I think that's a great thing
for Chris. Like Chris just had a second
team all-pro year. I think putting
Jordan Addison on the field with him in
allowing some of that coverage to shift
and to not always have him be the focal
point of things. I think this is a move
that can allow Chris Olave to be like a
1,500 yard receiver. Like I think
opportunities open up for everybody
here. Um Shaquille keeps getting better
get keeps getting more more confidence
in himself. All all that stuff I think
can just take this thing to um
heights that that it hasn't been at for
a while. Like this is
this is potentially the best wide
receiver combo they've had here since
the the BMW offense when it was Brandin
Cooks, Michael Thomas, and Willie Snead.
Like that that one year they had those
three guys that were all really really
good and then they broke it apart. I
think this is the best set of weapons
they've had since then specifically at
the wide receiver position. Maybe ever
though. Yeah, no no offense to those
guys. No no offense to the BMW, but this
should be better. If this pans out it
should be better. It's supposed to be
better with the investments they made in
Olave and Tyson now. Um
um I'm not going to say they're both
going to be better than Michael Thomas.
He's probably the best of all time, but
uh they should both be better than
Brandin Cooks was in New Orleans. That's
for sure. And and Valdes-Scantling, you
know, hopefully Valdes-Scantling can be
in the in the category of what Willie
Snead was for this team.
Willie Snead's a high bar, man. I know.
I know.
Willie Snead with Drew Brees is a high
bar.
>> to. I'm talking to the Willie Snead
uh uh fan club treasurer.
>> Willie was his best year that like 982
that year I think he had. Like he he's
he he was a baller. Like he he was
really really good. Yeah. Um that that
was a good up But yeah, you're right.
And look, that version of the offense
too Mike wasn't fully formed Mike yet.
Um
I'd still take Mike overall. I'd
probably take Mike over a combination of
Oh yeah. the top two. Give me give me
one Mike over Yes. But look, Jordan
Addison's a really really good player.
Uh My my esteem for Mike Thomas was just
crazy. We should have led with
Shaquille. I mean, yet another signal
that
you know, actions speak louder than
words. This this team is building around
Shaquille. They gave him a left guard
and a
speed in free agency with
A.J. Klein and uh Noah Fant. Now they're
giving him his his receiver. I mean,
it's it's go time with Tyler Shaquille.
That's that's what's going to determine
the success of this team, but they're
giving him a real chance to succeed.
It's what you want to see, too. Just go
in around him. Give him everything. Give
him every opportunity to succeed. These
guys
you know, become it. And at the end of
it at the end of this road it's going to
be interesting because they're going to
probably have to pick one of them. If
everything works out, it's going to be
one guy. Um
Who's it going to be? Like that I'm I'm
fascinated to see that in the future. Um
but for the time being I think it's it's
everybody rises and everybody, you know,
gets better together.
I'm excited about it. I would have liked
to see defense here, but
a TD getter is it just changes it just
changes things a little bit. Building
around the young QB like that feel of it
feels really you know, it's exciting.
It's an exciting time for the team.
I can't wait for Sundays, man. Like I'm
excited to see what these guys all do
together. I think he's going to be
really good in this offense and I think
we saw Kellen Moore really start to come
together last year once he had
the ability to convert third downs and
and open things up a little bit. And
there was a little bit more belief in
what could be done. And he was doing a
fantastic job of scheming people open.
Sometimes you can't tell you know,
exactly what's the quarterback, what's
the OC, but when people are running
free, that's your coach. The
quarterback's finding them, that's
great.
Kellen Moore with a handful of weapons,
I want to see what he's coming up with
cuz now he has two tight ends. He has
the running back that that fits his
offense. He's got two plus one at wide
receiver. Um I think he has some really
nice pieces and the quarterback, man, if
if Shaquille can just if Shaquille just
stays the same, let alone get better,
and I think he's going to get better. If
he just stays the same, um there's a lot
here that I think just the pieces around
him I I I think things can go to a
higher level. Completely agree. And yet
Caleb Downs was the guy I wanted uh them
to end up with in the realistic
scenarios, but um but that doesn't take
away my excitement for seeing what this
offense looks like with Jordan Addison.
All right, we're going to keep having
the breakdowns of this pick on New
Orleans. Stop football. Check us out
there. We'll be back tomorrow with a
full show, too. So keep it locked to the
channel. Uh appreciate you guys for
tuning in and I'll talk to you next
time.
>> [music]